Special Committee on the Structure of the University Records, 1967-1970 (bulk 1968-1969): Finding Aid AC044
University Archives
- Series 5: Faculty and Department Surveys, 1968; 2 boxes
  Series 5: Surveys is comprised of surveys from university department chairs, committees from throughout the university, and from faculty. Surveys were a fundamental vehicle through which the Special Committee was able to collect the opinions of the university community regarding the state of administration as it had existed and in what direction it should ultimately follow.
  Arranged alphabetically by university committee and department.
  - Admissions Committee, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Committee on Appointments and Advancements, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Advisory Committee on Policy, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Athletic Eligibility, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Committee on Structure Questionnaires, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Committees, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Conference Committee, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Course of Study Committee, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Departmental and Program Chairs, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Departmental and Program Chairs, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Departmental and Program Chairs, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Discipline, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Examinations and Standing, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Decision-Making Procedures of the University Faculty, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Faculty: Three Matters for Improvement, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Graduate School, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Honorary Degrees, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Library, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Princeton-Penn Accelerator, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Princeton University Conference, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Public Lectures, 1968; 1 folder (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Public Speaking and Debate, 1968; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Research in the Humanities and Social Sciences, 1968; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Schedule Committee, 1968; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Scholarships, 1968; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Scientific Research and Higgins Fund Committee, 1968; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Undergraduate Life, 1968; 1 folder (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Series 6: Literature, 1961-1972; 4 boxes
  Series 6: Literature, assembles newspaper, magazine, and journal articles found throughout the collection in distinct folders. They serve as a concrete body of knowledge that members of the committee, students, faculty, and staff shared during this time of momentous change.
  - Antioch College: Election of Some Trustees by Administrative Council, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Columbia, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Cornell University, 1968; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Literature: Democratization of Academic Administration, 1968-1970; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Literature: Democratization of College Governance, 1968-1969; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Literature: Democratization of College Governance, 1969; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Literature: Democratization of College Governance, 1970; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Literature: Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1969; 1970; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Literature: Princeton University Institutional Publications, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Literature: Miles, "The Pathology of Institutional Breakdown", undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Rufus Miles, Memorandum: Restructuring and Related Matters, 1968; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - New York University, 1968; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Norwegian Universities, Notes on Harry Eckstein, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Ombudsman, Notes on, from Michigan State and Others, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Princeton Strike, 1970; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - The Right of Reply from Nevada Compiled Laws, undated; 1 folder (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Literature (Author): Demonstrations, Confrontations, and Academic Business as Usual, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Literature (Author): The Political Involvement of Students: Where Freedom Begins and Ends, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Literature (Author): Viewpoints for the Study of the Administration of Higher Education, 1966; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Literature (Author): United States National Student Association. Bulletin, 1966; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Literature (Author): United States National Student Association. Codification of Policy, 1967-1968; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Literature (Author): United States National Student Association. What Makes a Campus Power Structure?, 1966; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Literature (Author): United States National Student Association., undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Literature (Author): The Student as University Resident, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Literature (Author): Procedural Due Process and State University Students, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Literature (Author): Campus Freedom and Order, 1968; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Literature (General): Democratization of Academic Administration, 1968; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Literature (General): Democratization of College Governance, 1968-1969; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Literature (General): Democratization of College Governance, circa 1969; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Literature (General): Democratization of College Governance, 1970; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Literature (General): Ombudsman, Notes on, From Michigan State and Others, undated; 1 folder (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Literature (Schools): Antioch College, Election of Some Trustees by Administrative Council, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Literature (Schools): Brown University, Community and Partnership: Student Conduct at Brown University, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Literature (Schools): Columbia University, Preliminary Proposals for the Creation of University Senate and a Student Assembly, 1968; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Literature (Schools): Columbia University, Who Rules Columbia?, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Literature (Schools): Columbia University, miscellaneous, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Literature (Schools): Columbia University, Crisis at Columbia: An Insider Report on the Rebellion at Columbia, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Literature (Schools): Columbia University, miscellaneous newspaper, 1968; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Literature (Schools): Columbia University, Sindler Commission Report, 1967; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Literature (Schools): Columbia Spectator, 1968; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Literature (Schools): Cornell University, Faculty Questionaire, 1968; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Literature (Schools): Michigan State University, A Report of the Faculty Committee on Student Affairs to the Academic Council, 1967; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Literature (Schools): New York University, circa 1968; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Literature (Schools): Norwegian Universities, Harry Eckstein, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Reports, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Short and Long Range Programs Intended to Increase the Faculty's Opportunity for Scholarship, 1961; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Princeton Alumni Weekly, 1969-1970; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Princeton University Institutional Publications, undated; 1 folder (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Report of the Ad Hoc on Princeton's Investments in Companies Operating in Southern Africa, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Princeton Strike, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Project Administration Guide, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, The Special Committee on the Structure of the University, 1968; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Special Committee on the Structure of the University, Bibliographies, 1972; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Special Committee to Examine Princeton's Relationship to the Institute for Defense Analysis, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Reports on the Undergraduate Life, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Literature (Schools): Princeton University, Students and the University, 1968; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Literature (Schools): Rochester University, Report of the Student Faculty Committee, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Literature (Schools): UC Berkeley, Study Commission on University Governance, 1968; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Literature (Schools): Wayne State University, Student Rights and Responsibilities, undated; 1 folder (Box 14, Folder 11)